I Am Bolt is a documentary film directed by Gabe Turner.
Fully authorized, access-all-areas feature doc on the hugely charismatic and
globally adored Usain Bolt – officially the fastest man alive.
With never-before-seen archive footage of his youth in Jamaica, through to original footage that will be captured at his fourth and final Olympic Games in
Rio, where he will compete for the gold in both the 100 and 200 metres races, for a third straight Games before his retirement in 2017.
I AM BOLT will reveal the man and define the legacy of this incredible athlete.
Himself, played by Usain Bolt.
Himself, played by Neymar.
Herself, played by Serena Williams.
I Am Bolt is a 2016 British biographical documentary sports film co-directed by
Benjamin Turner and Gabe Turner and produced by Leo Pearlman.
It is based on the life of Jamaican sprinter and three-time Olympic gold medalist and World Record
holder for 100m, 200m, 4×100m relay, Usain Bolt, the fastest man in recorded human history.
The film describes Bolt’s journey in winning nine gold medals
and the incidents surrounding the Olympic titles.
The film was released on 28 November 2016 in United Kingdom and then worldwide.
The film received mostly positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of interview, biography, tv
reporter, archive footage, sports documentary.